Guide to the James W. Forsyth Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Military Papers, 1865-1924; Series III; 0.25; (1 box); 0.25' (1 Box)
  - JAMES W. FORSYTH
    - Newspaper clippings, scrapbook (photocopies of originals), 1888-94, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folders 177-82
    - Newspaper clippings, loose pages and clippings (photocopies of originals), 1878-1906, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 183
  - WILLIAM D. FORSYTH
    - Commission as 1st Lieutenant in 1st Regiment, Ohio Volunteers, 1898 May 9
      See: Oversize, Box 11, folder 197
  - GUY V. HENRY
    Newspaper clippings (photocopies of
    - originals), 1891-96
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 184
    - Copy of Henry's answers to an 1870 interrogatory on Maynadier's conduct, 1895 Sep 7 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - "Adventures of American Army and Navy Offices" by Guy V. Henry in Harper's Weekly (photocopy of original), 1896 Dec 26
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 185
  - NELSON A. MILES
    - Letter from the Secretary of War, transmitting...correspondence with General Miles relative to the surrender of Geronimo (Sen. Ex. Doc. 117, 49th Cong. 2d Sess), 1887 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Copies of letters by Forsyth about Miles's behavior, [1891 Dec] (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Newspaper clippings (photocopies of originals), 1895, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 186
  - ANSON MILLS
    - Obituary (photocopy of original), 1924 Nov 5
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 187
  - MICHAEL V. SHERIDAN
    - Military Record of Colonel Michael V. Sheridan, Assistant Adjutant General, U.S. Army (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - P. H. SHERIDAN
    - Battles Fought by the Cavalry under the command of Major General P. H. Sheridan, U.S. Army, From May 4, 1864, to April 9, 1865 and Routes of the Raids..., ca. 1865
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 188
  - U.S. MILITARY - GENERAL
    - Records for services and goods received at Columbus Barracks, Ohio, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Newspaper clipping (photocopies of originals), 1893-1901, n.d.
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 189
- Photographs, 19th century; Series IV; 0.5; (1 box); 0.5' (1 Box)
  Photographs is arranged under topical headings. Within each subseries, material is arranged by format and studio location.
  - AMERICAN FIGURES
    - Cabinet Photographs
      - New York, N.Y., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 65)
      - Washington, D.C., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Carte-de-visites
      - Albany, N.Y., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - Chicago, Ill., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 68)
      - Cincinnati, Ohio, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 69)
      - Cleveland, Ohio, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 70)
      - Columbus, Ohio, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - East Saginaw, Mich., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 72)
      - Nashville, Tenn., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 73)
      - New York, N.Y., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 74)
      - Omaha, Neb., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 75)
      - Providence, R.I., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 76)
      - Washington, D.C., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 77)
      - Place unknown, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - FOREIGN FIGURES
    - Carte-de-visites
      - Canada, 1873 Apr 14 (Box 5, Folder 79)
      - England, ca. 1862 (Box 5, Folder 80)
      - France, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 81)
      - Prussia, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 82)
      - Turkey, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 83)
      - United States, 1864 (Box 5, Folder 84)
      - Place unknown, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - FORSYTH FAMILY AND FRIENDS
    - Cabinet photographs
      - Chicago, Ill., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 86)
      - Columbus, Ohio, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 87)
      - New York, N.Y., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - Carte-de-visites
      - Boston, Mass., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 89)
      - Cambridgeport, Mass., 1864 (Box 5, Folder 90)
      - Chicago, Ill., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 91)
      - Cincinnati, Ohio, 1862, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 92)
      - Cleveland, Ohio, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 93)
      - Columbus, Ohio, 1862, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 94)
      - Gamblin, Ohio, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 95)
      - Gloucester, Mass., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 96)
      - Junction City, Kan., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 97)
      - Madison, Wis., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 98)
      - New York, N.Y., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 99)
      - Philadelphia, Pa., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 100)
      - Utica, N.Y., 1864 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - Washington, D.C., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - Place unknown, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - Place unknown (tintypes), 19th century (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - Carte-de-visites
      - Chicago, Ill., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 105)
      - New York, N.Y., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 106)
      - Newport, R.I., 19th century (Box 5, Folder 107)
      - Place unknown, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 108)
- Forsyth Family Papers, 1890-1932; Series V; 0.25; (1 box); 0.25' (1 Box)
  Forsyth Family is arranged by individual's name. Each person's relationship to Graham is noted next to his or her name. Within each subseries, material is arranged chronologically (in the case of a photocopy the original date is used).
  - MRS. DALLAS BACHE (daughter)
    - Photograph
      See: Box 5, folder 91
    - Envelopes addressed to her, 1920, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - MRS. MARION F. FITZGERALD (daughter)
    - Divorce decree, 1897 May 11 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Letters, 1927, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - JAMES W. FORSYTH
    - Receipts, 1890 Apr 8 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - Receipts, 1894 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Receipts, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 114-16)
    - Receipts, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 117-19)
    - Receipts, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 120-22)
    - Receipts, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Memorandum of thanks from Kansas Brigade, Uniform Rank, Knights of Pythias, Wichita, Kansas, 1891 May 21
      See: Oversize, Box 11, folder 198
    - Newspaper clippings (photocopies of originals), 1893-1903
      See: Oversize, Box 10, folder 190
    - Statement on the Washington Land Account to the estate of J. W. Forsyth, 1909 Mar 1 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 125)
- Dennison Family Papers, 1876-95; Series VI; 1; (3 boxes); 1' (3 Boxes, one bound volume)
  Dennison Family Papers consists of chronologically arranged receipts and a publication.
  - Receipt, 1882 Jul (Box 7, Folder 126)
  - Receipt, 1883 Jul (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Receipt, 1889 Nov (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Receipts, 1890 (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Receipts, 1891 (Box 7, Folder 130-41)
  - Receipts, 1892 Jan-Mar (Box 7, Folder 142-44)
  - Receipts, 1892 Apr-Dec (Box 8, Folder 145-50)
  - Receipts, 1893-94 (Box 8, Folder 151-58)
  - Receipts, 1895 Jan-Feb (Box 9, Folder 159-67)
  - Receipts, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 168-70)
  - William Dennison's copy of A Trip to the Yellowstone National Park in July, August, and September, 1875. From the Journal of General W. E. Strong. Washington, 1876 (Box 9, Folder 170.1)
- Oversize, 3.17; (3 boxes); 3.0' (2 Boxes)
  Oversize contains oversize material from Series II, III, and V. The arrangement, which is based on size, parallels that of the collection.
  - SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE
    - Letterpress copybook, 1877-1885 (Box 9a, Folder 170.2)
  - SERIES II. WOUNDED KNEE PAPERS
    - "Field return of Seventh Cavalry in the field commanded by Colonel James W. Forsyth...", 1890 Dec (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 171)
    - Newspaper clippings (photocopies of originals), 1891 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 172-73)
  - SERIES III. MILITARY PAPERS
    - Dallas Bache
      - Newspaper clipping, obituary (photocopy of original), 1902 Jun 7 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 174)
    - Henry C. Corbin
      - Newspaper clipping (photocopy of original), 1895 Oct 3 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 175)
    - James W. Forsyth
      - Military History of James W. Forsyth, Major 10th Cavalry, Lieutenant Colonel and Aide-de-Camp to the Lieutenant General U.S.A., 1872 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 176)
      - Newspaper clippings, scrapbook (photocopies of originals), 1888-94, n.d. (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 177-82)
      - Newspaper clippings, loose pages and clippings (photocopies of originals), 1878-1906, n.d. (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 183)
    - Guy V. Henry
      - Newspaper clippings (photocopies of originals), 189-96 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 184)
      - "Adventures of American Army and Navy Offices" by Guy V. Henry in Harper's Weekly (photocopy of original), 1896 Dec 26 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 185)
    - Nelson A. Miles
      - Newspaper clippings (photocopies of originals), 1895, n.d. (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 186)
    - Anson Mills
      - Obituary (photocopy of original), 1924 Nov 5 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 187)
    - P. H. Sheridan
      - Battles Fought by the Cavalry under the command of Major General P. H. Sheridan, U.S. Army, From May 4, 1864, to April 9, 1865 and Routes of the Raids..., ca. 1865 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 188)
    - U.S. Military - General
      - Newspaper clipping (photocopies of originals), 1893-1901, n.d. (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 189)
  - SERIES V. FORSYTH FAMILY
    - James W. Forsyth
      - Newspaper clippings (photocopies of originals), 1893-1903 (Box 10 (Oversize), Folder 190)
  - SERIES II. WOUNDED KNEE PAPERS
    - "Scene of the fight with Big Foots Band, Dec 29th, 1890, showing position of troops when first shot was fired. Wounded Knee - Correct map as authenticated by members of Reg. in fight. J. F. B." (manuscript map), [1891] (Box 11 (Oversize), Folder 191)
    - Scene of the fight with Big Foots Band, Dec 29th, 1890, showing position of troops when first shot was fired. From sketches by Lieut. S. A. Cloman, Act'g Engr. Officer, Division of the Missouri (blueprint map with annotations), [1891] (Box 11 (Oversize), Folder 192)
    - Scene of the fight with Big Foot's Band, December 29th, 1890, showing the position of the troops when first shot was fired. From sketches by Lt. S. A. Cloman, Acting Engineer Officer, Division of the Missouri (printed map), [1891] (Box 11 (Oversize), Folder 193)
    - Map of the Battlefield of Wounded Knee Creek with marks indicating position of troops, Indians, and events (blueprint map), [1891] (Box 11 (Oversize), Folder 194)
    - Map No. 1. To Illustrate the recent campaign against hostile Sioux Indians of Dakota showing different positions of troops from the beginning to the surrender in January 1891 (printed map) (Box 11 (Oversize), Folder 195)
  - SERIES III. MILITARY PAPERS
    - James W. Forsyth
      - Appointment to rank of Brigadier General by Brevet, 1866 Jul 30 (Box 11 (Oversize), Folder 196)
    - William D. Forsyth
      - Commission as 1st Lieutenant in 1st Regiment, Ohio Volunteers, 1898 May 9 (Box 11 (Oversize), Folder 197)
  - SERIES V. FORSYTH FAMILY PAPERS
    - James W. Forsyth
      - Memorandum of thanks from Kansas Brigade, Uniform Rank, Knights of Pythias, Wichita, Kansas, 1891 May 21 (Box 11 (Oversize), Folder 198)